Tim Hulak

Rancho Cucamonga, California, United States

timhulak@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/tim-hulak-b7520a75

Summary

Data professional with experience in analysis, programming, and logistics. Career highlights include process automation, recommendation system, and Business Intelligence Dashboards. Academic background focuses on Python, SQL, R, Tableau, and Excel while attending the USC Viterbi School of Engineering and Applied Data Science/Business Analytics while attending Syracuse University. Interests include Financial Analytics, investing, music, and sports.

Experience

cm Senior Analyst, Logistics Operations

CarMax

Oct 2019 - Present (2 years 7 months +)

- Plan and execute cross-country movement of vehicles within the Hub-and-Spoke network in collaboration with logistics planners, logistics managers, and third-party logistics associates.
- Develop tools for analysis and process automation using MS Excel and Python-Django
- Train and develop junior analyst skills in Python, SQL, Excel, statistics, and analysis.
- "Pulse" Captain: Analyze company survey results and advocate for associates to management.

Instructor

May 2017 - Jul 2020 (3 years 3 months)

Teaching guitar, bass, ukulele, and piano to a wide variety of students via my personal curriculum.

👼 Industrial Engineering: Feeder Data Analyst

UPS

Feb 2019 - Oct 2019 (9 months)

Find solutions for logistical data needs via advanced Microsoft Excel, some Microsoft Access, and developing applications in Python.

Flow Control PT Supervisor

UPS

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019 (2 months)

Direct the flow of packages from the unloading bays and pass maintenance requests to the Plant Engineering department via the Hub and Feeder Control System. Maintain an hourly log of volume via Microsoft Excel Web App. Query the automated system via Microsoft Access to ensure accurate package delivery.

Package Handler

UPS

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019 (4 months)

I took the initiative to collect, clean, and visualize data via Excel regarding packages that were loading into the wrong trailer. Over a 3 month period, I presented my supervisors with daily and weekly analysis/ visualizations to help make better educated decisions and ensure accuracy in package delivery. My day-to-day duties included loading, unloading, and sorting packages at the UPS HUB facility.



Instructor

The Guitar Center Company

Jun 2016 - May 2017 (1 year)

Teaching guitar, bass, and piano to a wide variety of students via the Guitar Center curriculum and my own supplemental material.

E-4 Air Support Operations Operator (7242)

United States Marine Corps

Dec 2008 - Nov 2016 (8 years)

Processed immediate air requests in the Direct Air Support Center (DASC) on a crew of 7-10 Marines. Earned the Outstanding Volunteer Service Medal for 600+ hours of volunteer work at my local Veterans Resource Center. Achieved the Non-Commissioned Officer rank of Corporal (E-4).

Guitar and Piano Instructor

Sep 2014 - Jul 2015 (11 months)

Teaching basic to intermediate level guitar and piano.

Green Team

Securitas Security Services USA, Inc.

Jul 2013 - Nov 2013 (5 months)

Maintaining good order and discipline at the Pomona LA County fair and Oktoberfest.

Veterans Resource Center Staff Member

Chaffey College

Aug 2011 - Jul 2013 (2 years)

Assisted military veterans obtain their G.I. Bill benefits and focus on educational success.

Education

Syracuse University

Master of Science - MS, Applied Data Science

Oct 2020 - Jul 2022

Oct 2020 - Jul 2022

The program focuses on database administration/management, statistical analysis and decision making, R programming of statistical/machine learning models, business analytics (including financial analytics, marketing analytics, and Google Analytics), Natural Language Processing, Big Data analytics, and scripting for data analysis using Python.



USC Viterbi Graduate Programs

Certification, Data Analytics

2018 - 2019

24-week Data Analytics Bootcamp

Learned fundamental and specialized skills in data analytics, including Python, JavaScript, Excel, SQL and Databases. Received a hands-on, classroom learning experience, conducting robust analytics on a host of real-world problems.

University of Southern California

Master of Music (M.M), Studio/Jazz Guitar 2017 - 2018

Completed 14/30 credit hours before pursuing other professional and educational goals.



San Francisco State University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Music 2015 - 2017 Guitar emphasis



Chaffey College

Associate of Arts (A.A.), Fine Arts and Music 2011 - 2014

Studied music with a guitar emphasis and took courses for matriculation

Licenses & Certifications



Master Excel for Data Science (8 Course Learning Path) - Lynda.com

© Excel Statistics / Data Analytics - Udemy UC-C15F4R2J

Statistics for Data Science and Business Analysis - Udemy UC-QQSKIDP7

Probability and Statistics for Business and Data Science - Udemy UC-3E3S8IQH

Data Science Methodology - Coursera
JLUWER8Q9VDH

Databases and SQL for Data Science - Coursera
P2QSL5Y8CZ5W



3X9GSNPAZBMK

- **Data Visualization with Python** Coursera
- Machine Learning with Python Coursera FQ2KXEAR39DR
- SQL Certification Course Programming Hub 288863
- in Python Essential Training LinkedIn
- in Master Python for Data Science LinkedIn
- in Using Python with Excel LinkedIn
- n pandas Essential Training LinkedIn
- in Using Python for Automation LinkedIn
- in Building Tools with Python LinkedIn
- in Python Automation and Testing LinkedIn
- n Data Ingestion with Python LinkedIn
- in NumPy Data Science Essential Training LinkedIn
- in pandas for Data Science LinkedIn
- SQL Fundamentals Sololearn 1060-9946415
- in Data Science Foundations: Python Scientific Stack LinkedIn
- in Learning Data Science: Ask Great Questions LinkedIn

- in Tableau Essential Training LinkedIn
- Azure Data Studio Essential Training LinkedIn
- in Programming Foundations: Databases LinkedIn
- in SQL Essential Training LinkedIn
- in SQL: Data Reporting and Analysis LinkedIn
- in Become a SQL Developer LinkedIn
- Program Databases with Transact-SQL LinkedIn
- The Basics LinkedIn
- Introduction to Data Science Specialization Coursera
 5BQGLRJLFZMD
- Data Science Math Skills Duke University | Coursera U7HS3N4JJLK5

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Microsoft Excel • R • Statistical Data Analysis • Data Analysis • Business Analysis • Statistics • Machine Learning • Big Data • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)